{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The yield of the antibiotic depends upon", "opta": "pH of the medium", "optb": "age of the inoculum", "optc": "composition of the medium", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During which phase of growth of Penicillium chrysogenum maximum antibiotic production takes place", "opta": "during the first phase", "optb": "during the second phase", "optc": "during the third phase", "optd": "same in all the phases", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fermentation medium for oxytetracyclin (terramycin) consist of", "opta": "CSL, starch, (NH4)2 SO4, sodium chloride and CaCO3", "optb": "CSL, (NH4)2 SO4, sodium chloride and CaCO3", "optc": "CSL, starch,(NH4)2 SO4, ammonium chloride and CaCO3", "optd": "CSL,(NH4)2 SO4, ammonium chloride and CaCO3", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "pH of the fermentation medium for chlorotetracyclins is", "opta": "5-6", "optb": "6-7", "optc": "7-8", "optd": "8-9", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At normal pH, penicillin remains in", "opta": "aqueous phase", "optb": "solvent phase", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "precipitates", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At acidic pH, penicillin remains in", "opta": "aqueous phase", "optb": "solvent phase", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "precipitates", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chlorotetracyclin is soluble in", "opta": "organic solvents", "optb": "water", "optc": "ether", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Penicillin is produced by", "opta": "aerobic fermentation", "optb": "anaerobic fermentation", "optc": "aerobic fermentation followed by anaerobic fermentation", "optd": "anaerobic fermentation followed by aerobic fermentation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Penicillin is recovered after fermentation as", "opta": "potassium penicillin", "optb": "calcium penicillin", "optc": "sodium penicillin", "optd": "penicillin only", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Media composition for the production of streptomycin is", "opta": "soybean meal, glucose, peptone, malt extract, sodium chloride", "optb": "soybean meal, glucose, peptone, malt extract, ammonium chloride", "optc": "soybean meal, glucose, peptone, malt extract, calcium carbonate", "optd": "soybean meal, glucose, peptone, malt extract, ammonium sulphate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following organism(s) produce(s) tetracycline?", "opta": "Steptomyces aureofaciens", "optb": "Steptomyces ramosus", "optc": "Nocardia sulphurea", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Media used for the production of chlorotetracyclin consists of", "opta": "sugar, corn steep liquor, CaCO3, (NH4)2SO4 and NH4 Cl", "optb": "corn steep liquor, CaCO3 and (NH4)2SO4", "optc": "sugar, CaCO3 and (NH4)2SO4", "optd": "corn steep liquor, CaCO3, (NH4)2SO4 and NH4 Cl", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following precursor is added in the medium to get penicillin G?", "opta": "Phenyl carbamic acid", "optb": "Phenyl acetic acid", "optc": "Ammonium sulphate", "optd": "Ammonium chloride", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "High yield of chlorotetracyclin requires", "opta": "no aeration", "optb": "continuous aeration", "optc": "aeration which does not affect the yield", "optd": "controlled aeration", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Streptomycin is produced by", "opta": "S. griseus", "optb": "S. griseoflavus", "optc": "S. aerofaciens", "optd": "S. ramosus", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following event occurs during second phase of growth of P. chrysogenum?", "opta": "Synthesis of penicillin is high", "optb": "Mycelial mass increases", "optc": "pH increase", "optd": "Both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Inoculum preparation for the fermentation medium for penicillin takes place on", "opta": "wheat seeds", "optb": "barley seeds", "optc": "rice seeds", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Antibiotics are typically produced in fed batch reactors because", "opta": "antibiotic yields are generally higher when cells enter the stationary phase", "optb": "the precursors are often toxic to the cells", "optc": "antibiotic yields are generally higher when cell growth slows", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following event occurs during third phase of growth of P chrysogenum?", "opta": "Concentration of antibiotic increases in the medium", "optb": "Autolysis of the medium starts", "optc": "Slight rise in pH due to liberation of ammonia", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vegetable oil, (corn oil or soybean oil) added in the fermentation medium for penicillin, act as", "opta": "source of nutrients", "optb": "carbon source", "optc": "antifoam agent", "optd": "both (a) and (c)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following changes occur during first phase of growth of Penicillium chrysogenum?", "opta": "Growth of mycelia occurs", "optb": "Ammonia is liberated in the medium", "optc": "Lactic acid present in the corn steep liquor is utilized at the maximum rate", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}